=The Origin of Eternity=
= أصل الخلود =
=Episode 13=
= الحلقة 13 =
Don't tell me
لا تخبرني
you're clueless about such things.
أنت جاهل بمثل هذه الأشياء.
Who says I'm clueless about it?
من قال أنني جاهل بذلك؟
What are you trying to do?
ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟
Here I am lying by your side.
ها أنا أكذب بجانبك.
We have reached the point where we have to do it.
لقد وصلنا إلى النقطة حيث يتعين علينا القيام بذلك.
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Until you become my husband,
حتى تصبح زوجي ،
it won't be too late for us to do this and that.
لن يكون الوقت قد فات بالنسبة لنا للقيام بهذا وذاك.
This
هذا
and that.
وذلك.
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
You ordered me to serve in the palace.
لقد أمرتني بالخدمة في القصر.
It's a long night.
إنها ليلة طويلة.
Are you saying I don't have to do anything?
هل تقول أنني لست مضطرًا لفعل أي شيء؟
Just stay with me
فقط ابق معي
as you are now
كما انت الان
so I can see you.
لذا أستطيع أن أراك.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Do you like it, Your Majesty?
هل يعجبك جلالة الملك؟
Can you guess the song
هل يمكنك تخمين الأغنية
I played just now?
لقد لعبت الآن؟
I only know how to fight and kill.
أنا أعرف فقط كيف أقاتل وأقتل.
I don't know anything
لا اعرف شيئا
about these elegant things.
حول هذه الأشياء الأنيقة.
It's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
If you want to learn,
إذا كنت تريد أن تتعلم ،
I can teach you.
أستطيع تعليمك.
No need.
لا حاجة.
I tried when I was young.
حاولت عندما كنت صغيرا.
I find it boring.
أجد أنها مملة.
It's not as interesting as using swords.
إنه ليس ممتعًا مثل استخدام السيوف.
That was because the tutor made it boring.
كان ذلك لأن المعلم جعلها مملة.
How about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
Let's play a game.
لنلعب لعبة.
You'll listen and differentiate the notes.
سوف تستمع وتفرق بين الملاحظات.
If you make the wrong guess,
إذا قمت بالتخمين الخاطئ ،
you'll have to drink a cup of wine.
سيكون عليك شرب كوب من النبيذ.
All right.
حسنًا.
What if I make the right guess?
ماذا لو قدمت التخمين الصحيح؟
What can
ماذا بالامكان
you give me?
انت اعطني؟
If you make the right guess,
إذا قمت بالتخمين الصحيح ،
I'll kiss you.
سوف اقبلك.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Sounds fun.
يبدو ممتع.
It's "Gong."
إنه "غونغ".
You made the wrong guess.
لقد أخطأت في التخمين.
It was "Shang."
كان "شانغ".
Again.
مرة أخرى.
It's "Zhi."
إنها "زي".
It's wrong again, Your Majesty.
إنه خطأ مرة أخرى يا صاحب الجلالة.
The correct answer
الجواب الصحيح
is "Yu."
هل أنت.
It's a pity you didn't guess any of them correctly.
إنه لأمر مؤسف أنك لم تخمن أيًا منهم بشكل صحيح.
How about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
I'll drink this cup
سأشرب هذا الكأس
for you.
لك.
That's more like it.
وهذا أشبه ذلك.
Are you upset?
هل انت منزعج؟
What's there to be upset about?
ما الذي يدعو إلى الانزعاج؟
The dignified Crown Prince of the Ling Empire
ولي العهد المحترم لإمبراطورية لينغ
is proficient in such decadent music.
يبرع في مثل هذه الموسيقى المنحطة.
No wonder Ling Empire
لا عجب في إمبراطورية لينغ
can't defeat Great Sheng.
لا يمكن هزيمة جريت شنغ.
- Your Majesty! Your Majesty! - Please stop.
- جلالة الملك!  جلالة الملك!  - توقف أرجوك.
I have a jar of great wine
لدي جرة من النبيذ الرائع
to share with you.
أن أطلعكم.
You ignorant man of the Ling Empire!
أنت رجل جاهل من إمبراطورية لينغ!
Believe it or not, I'll cut you!
صدق أو لا تصدق ، سأقطعك!
Insolence.
الوقاحة.
You ignored the instructions of the eunuchs
لقد تجاهلت تعليمات الخصيان
and barged into the Imperial Garden.
واقتحموا الحديقة الإمبراطورية.
What's your intention?
ما هي نيتك؟
You put aside my loyalty
أنت تضع ولائي جانبا
and favor a hostage from Ling Empire!
وفضلوا رهينة من إمبراطورية لينغ!
What's the meaning of this then?
ما معنى هذا إذن؟
You're not in a position
أنت لست في موقف
to meddle in what happens in my chamber.
للتدخل فيما يحدث في غرفتي.
I'm the only Lord with a different surname in Great Sheng.
أنا الرب الوحيد الذي يحمل لقبًا مختلفًا في Great Sheng.
You're nothing but a pretty boy from Ling Empire.
أنت لست سوى فتى جميل من Ling Empire.
You don't even deserve to carry my shoes!
أنت لا تستحق حتى أن تحمل حذائي!
Guards!
حراس!
Take Lord Yong away!
خذ اللورد يونغ بعيدًا!
I can walk myself!
أستطيع أن أمشي بنفسي!
Get out of my way!
ابتعد عن طريقي!
Are you done reflecting on your mistake?
هل انتهيت من التفكير في خطأك؟
I did nothing wrong.
لم أفعل أي شئ خاطئ.
If I did anything wrong,
إذا ارتكبت أي خطأ ،
it was loving you too much, Your Majesty.
كان يحبك كثيرا يا جلالة الملك.
I'm the ruler and you're a subject.
أنا الحاكم وأنت فاعل.
If I want you dead,
إذا كنت أريدك ميتا ،
you'll have to die.
عليك أن تموت.
As a subject,
كموضوع،
you barged into the sleeping chambers
اقتحمتم غرف النوم
and defied my orders.
وتحدت أوامري.
You claimed to love me.
لقد زعمت أنك تحبني.
Are you saying your feelings for me
هل تقول مشاعرك لي
mean you can place yourself above loyalty?
يعني يمكنك أن تضع نفسك فوق الولاء؟
It was
كان
a moment of confusion.
لحظة ارتباك.
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
If you realized your mistake,
إذا أدركت خطأك ،
I won't pursue it anymore.
لن أتابعها بعد الآن.
When I was the Crown Heir,
عندما كنت ولي العهد ،
it was you who strongly supported me to ascend the throne.
كنت أنت من دعمتني بقوة لاعتلاء العرش.
I have fought side by side with you over the years.
لقد قاتلت معك جنبًا إلى جنب على مر السنين.
I do
أفعل
have feelings for you.
لدي مشاعر تجاهك.
Your Majesty...
جلالة الملك ...
But I only see you as a brother,
لكني فقط أراك كأخ
not a romantic partner.
لا شريك رومانسي.
In the end,
في النهاية،
I still can't be compared to the pretty boy from Ling Empire.
ما زلت لا يمكن مقارنتي بالفتى الجميل من Ling Empire.
You don't need to compare yourself to Bai Ze.
لا تحتاج إلى مقارنة نفسك بـ Bai Ze.
He's just someone who sleeps next to me.
إنه مجرد شخص ينام بجواري.
But you're
لكنك أنت
my one and only loyal and brave general.
جنرالي الوحيد المخلص والشجاع.
♪Wandered off from the crowd♪
تجول بعيدًا عن الحشد ♪
♪As more wonderful things await♪
♪ كما تنتظر المزيد من الأشياء الرائعة
♪A sunset from the past resurfaced♪
انعكاس غروب الشمس من الماضي
♪Thousands of sailboats drifted in the sea of clouds♪
جرفت آلاف المراكب الشراعية في بحر السحب
♪And docked at different piers♪
♪ ورست على أرصفة مختلفة ♪
♪Only the catkin willow and my graying hair remained♪
فقط صفصاف القطة وشعري الشيب بقي
♪Let's take on♪
♪ لنأخذ
♪Another year♪
♪ سنة أخرى ♪
♪I traveled alone toward daytime as I waved aside the night♪
سافرت لوحدي في النهار بينما كنت ألوح جانباً في الليل
♪The tapping rain♪
مطر التنصت ♪
♪Awakened the sorrow♪
أيقظ الحزن
♪I'm crying out in loneliness amid pandemonium♪
♪ أنا أبكي في عزلة وسط الهرج والمرج
♪I endured countless ordeals from worldly entanglement♪
لقد تحملت محن لا حصر لها من التشابك الدنيوي ♪
♪Knowing how difficult things are for the first time♪
معرفة مدى صعوبة الأمور لأول مرة ♪
♪After you overcome the vicissitudes of life♪
بعد أن تتغلب على تقلبات الحياة
♪Only then do you understand the fickleness of the world♪
"عندها فقط تفهم تقلب العالم"
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪